T. JORDAN DUKES

1541 Crosstimbers Drive Louisville, Kentucky 40245 (270) 791-4049

t.jordan.dukes@gmail.com

Professional Summary

I have spent over five years working in the IT field as a programmer and technology analyst. As a technology analyst I was responsible for setting up, troubleshooting, and maintaining user workstations, software, and networking infrastructure. As a programmer analyst I was responsible for deploying, training, and troubleshooting third-party software. I was also responsible for designing, developing, and deploying several .Net software solutions. These included web forms, Windows forms, and Windows services coded in VB, C#, and ASP all using the .Net framework. All of these solutions were heavily database driven using Microsoft Sql Server 2005, Sql Server 2008, and MySql.

Technical Skills

Software: Microsoft Visual Studios 2002, Visual Studios 2008, Visual Studios 2010, Visual Studios 2012, SQL Server 2005, SQL Server 2008, Team Foundation Server, and VNC.

Languages: C#.NET, VB.NET, ASP.NET, JavaScript, jQuery, jQueryUI, Razor, HTML, XML.

Databases: MySQL, SQL Server 2005, SQL Server 2008, mongoDB.

Industries: Education and healthcare.

Operating Systems: Windows 98, Windows 2000, Windows XP, Windows Vista, Windows 7, Windows 8, Windows Server 2003, Ubuntu 12.

Professional Experience

.NET Engineer Advanced

ZirMed

August 2011 – Present

Louisville, Kentucky

Worked on the remits team designing and developing new products while maintaining, fixing, and rewriting existing code base.

Accomplishments:

- Designed, developed, implemented, and supported multiple .NET web and Windows solutions.
- Rewrote existing web pages and stored procedures to be more efficient and better performing.
- Helped re-architect remits source code to meet update ZirMed architecture standards.

RxCrossroads

March 2011 – August 2011

.NET Developer

Louisville, Kentucky

Worked with employees from different departments and companies to design, develop, implement, and test solutions for transferring, storing, and reporting various types of information. Worked closely with these same people to troubleshoot and fix issues with existing systems.

Accomplishments:

- Designed, developed, and implemented multiple .NET web and Windows solutions using ASP.NET,
 - C#.NET and SQLServer.
- Researched, identified, and fixed bugs within existing RxCrossroads software.
- Communicated across multiple departments and companies to design, develop, and implement multiple .NET solutions.

ZirMed

May 2009 – March 2011 Louisville, Kentucky

.NET Developer

Initially worked on the ZirMed support team researching, investigating, and fixing problems within the ZirMed website and applications. Responsible for writing "rules" and "premaps" used internally by ZirMed. Promoted to the claims team where I took on large projects pertaining to ZirMed's claim processing solution. Helped design, architect, and develop projects that were given to me in an efficient and timely manner.

Accomplishments:

- Designed, built, and implemented multiple .NET web solutions utilizing ASP.NET, C#.NET, and SQLServer both individually and with a team of colleagues.
- Worked independently and closely with a team of peers to design, build, and implement multiple .NET Windows Services using C#.NET and SQLServer.
- Ported existing Windows based .Net applications to .Net Windows services.
- Researched, identified, and fixed bugs within the ZirMed suite of products.
- Worked intimately for over a year and a half with Visual Studios 2008 and the .NET 3.5 and 4.0 framework.
- Worked intimately for over a year and a half with Microsoft SQL Server 2005.

Trover Health System

August 2007 – March 2009

Programmer Analyst

Madisonville, Kentucky

Worked with employees from different departments to provide software based .NET framework solutions for their needs. Worked closely with a team to implement and support high level software used throughout Trover Health Systems and to provide quick and reliable solutions to key problems.

Accomplishments:

- Implemented 3rd party software solutions campus wide.
- Designed, built, and implemented two .NET web applications built with ASP.NET and MYSQL.
 One of these is used campus wide. Both systems were designed, developed, and implemented by myself. Both systems required extensive requirement gathering to meet end user needs.
- Designed, built, and implemented several .NET windows applications based upon various user needs. These applications provided a specific functionality such as an alarm, document parsing, and file conversions.
- Worked intimately for two years with the Visual Studios 2002 .NET environment including: ASP,
 C#. and VB.
- Worked intimately for two years with MYSQL through HeidiSQL using it as a back end for .NET web applications.
- Gained valuable insight and experience gathering requirements from professionals outside the IT field.

Muhlenberg County Board of Education

May 2004 – August 2007

Technology Analyst

Greenville, Kentucky

Analyzed, installed, fixed and maintained various technology systems. With an emphasis on troubleshooting, minimizing system and user concerns. Concerns and issues included but were not limited to Networking, software, hardware, and misunderstanding issues. Instrumental in the development, implementation and maintenance of a team that worked efficiently and expeditiously as a part of an excellent I.S. Department.

Education

Western Kentucky University
Bachelor of Science, Computer Science

August 2003 – May 2007 Bowling Green, Kentucky